<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE library PUBLIC "-//Boost//DTD BoostBook XML V1.0//EN" 
"../../../tools/boostbook/dtd/boostbook.dtd">

<!-- Copyright (c) 2001-2004 CrystalClear Software, Inc.
     Subject to the Boost Software License, Version 1.0. 
     (See accompanying file LICENSE_1_0.txt or  http://www.boost.org/LICENSE_1_0.txt)
-->

<section id="date_time.design_concepts">
  <title>Design Concepts 设计概念</title>

  <para>
    A large part of the genesis of this library has been the observation that few date-time libraries are built in a fashion that allows customization and extension. A typical example, the calendar logic is built directly into the date class. Or the clock retrieval functions are built directly into the time class. These design decisions usually make it impossible to extend or change the library behavior. At a more fundamental level, there are usually assumptions about the resolution of time representation or the gregorian calendar. <sbr/>
    设计该库的很大一个原因是因为看到很多有日期时间库是按照允许进行定制和扩展的风格来建立的。
    一个典型的例子就是，日历逻辑直接创建在日期类中。又或者，时钟读取功能直接构建在时间类中。
    这些设计通常使得我们不可能扩展或修改库的行为。在更为基础的层次上，通常都假定了时间表示法的分辨率或是假定使用了格里历。
  </para>
  <para>
    Often times, the result is that a project must settle for a less than complete library because of a requirement for high resolution time representation or other assumptions that do not match the implementation of the library. This is extremely unfortunate because development of a library of this sort is far from a trivial task. <sbr/>
    多数时候，结果是一个项目必须满足于无法得到一个完整的库，因为对时间表示法的高分辨率要求或是其它假定无法与库的实现相匹配。
    这是非常不幸的，因为开始这样一个库远不是一件简单的工作。
  </para>
  <para>
    While the design is far from perfect the current design is far more flexible than any date-time library the author is aware of. It is expected that the various aspects of extensibility will be better documented in future versions. Information about the design goals of the library is <link linkend="date_time.design_goals">summarized here</link>. <sbr/>
    由于没有好的设计，作者所知的任何一个日期时间库的设计都不够灵活。在未来的版本中，我们期望可以有更多方面的扩展性。
    有关本库的设计目标的信息请参见 <link linkend="date_time.design_goals">这里的总结</link>。
  </para>
</section>
