<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//Boost//DTD BoostBook XML V1.0//EN"
  "http://www.boost.org/tools/boostbook/dtd/boostbook.dtd">
<!--
Copyright Douglas Gregor 2001-2004
Copyright Frank Mori Hess 2007-2009

Distributed under the Boost Software License, Version 1.0. (See accompanying
file LICENSE_1_0.txt or copy at http://www.boost.org/LICENSE_1_0.txt)
-->
<section last-revision="$Date: 2007-06-12 14:01:23 -0400 (Tue, 12 Jun 2007) $">
  <title>Introduction 介绍</title>

  <para>The Boost.Signals2 library is an implementation of a managed
  signals and slots system. Signals represent callbacks with multiple
  targets, and are also called publishers or events in similar
  systems. Signals are connected to some set of slots, which are
  callback receivers (also called event targets or subscribers), which
  are called when the signal is "emitted."<sbr/>
  Boost.Signals2 库实现了一个可控的信号插槽系统。信号代表了具有多个目标的回调， 
  在类似的系统中也称为发布者或事件。信号与某组插槽相连接，插槽即回调的接收者 
  （也称为事件目标或订阅者），它们在信号“发出”时被调用。</para>

  <para>Signals and slots are managed, in that signals and slots (or,
  more properly, objects that occur as part of the slots) can track
  connections and are capable of automatically disconnecting signal/slot
  connections when either is destroyed. This enables the user to make
  signal/slot connections without expending a great effort to manage the
  lifetimes of those connections with regard to the lifetimes of all
  objects involved.<sbr/>
  信号和插槽是可控的，因为信号和插槽（或严格地说是作为插槽出现的对象）跟踪所有的连接， 
  并能够在信号或插槽销毁时自动断开信号/插槽的连接。这让使用者能够在建立信号/插槽连接的同时， 
  不必费力地根据相关对象的生命期去管理那些连接的生命期。</para>

  <para>When signals are connected to multiple slots, there is a
  question regarding the relationship between the return values of the
  slots and the return value of the signals. Boost.Signals2 allows the
  user to specify the manner in which multiple return values are
  combined.<sbr/>
  当信号连接多个插槽时，插槽的返回值和信号的返回值之间是什么关系呢？这是个问题。 
  Boost.Signals2 允许用户合并多个返回值，并指定合并的方式。</para>

  <section>
    <title>Signals2</title>
    <para>This documentation describes a thread-safe variant of the
    original Boost.Signals library.  There have been some changes to
    the interface to support thread-safety, mostly with respect to
    automatic connection management.  This implementation was written by
    Frank Mori Hess.  Acknowledgements are also due to Timmo Stange, Peter
    Dimov, and Gottlob Frege for ideas and feedback, and to Douglas Gregor
    for the original version of Boost.Signals this effort was based on.
    <sbr/>
    本文描述的是原 Boost.Signals 库的一个线程安全的变体。接口有所更改以支持线程安全，
    主要是在自动连接管理方面。本实现由 Frank Mori Hess 编写。同时感谢 Timmo Stange、Peter Dimov，
    和 Gottlob Frege 的意见和反馈，并感谢 Douglas Gregor，基于他的 Boost.Signals 才会有这个成果。</para>
  </section>
</section>
