<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE library PUBLIC "-//Boost//DTD BoostBook XML V1.0//EN" 
"../../../tools/boostbook/dtd/boostbook.dtd">

<!-- Copyright (c) 2001-2004 CrystalClear Software, Inc.
     Subject to the Boost Software License, Version 1.0. 
     (See accompanying file LICENSE_1_0.txt or  http://www.boost.org/LICENSE_1_0.txt)
-->

<section id="date_time.domain_concepts">
  <title>Domain Concepts 领域概念</title>

  <para>
    The date time domain is rich in terminology and problems. 
    The following is a brief introduction to the concepts you 
    will find reflected in the library. <sbr/>
    日期时间领域有大量术语和问题。以下对你将会在本库碰到的一些概念作一个简要的介绍。
  </para>
  <para>
    The library supports 3 basic temporal types:<sbr/>
    本库支持3种基本的时间类型：
    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
	<emphasis role="strong">Time Point</emphasis> -- Specifier 
	for a location in the time continuum.<sbr/>
    <emphasis role="strong">时间点</emphasis> -- 在时间连续统中的一个特定位置。
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<emphasis role="strong">Time Duration</emphasis> -- A 
	length of time unattached to any point on the time continuum.<sbr/>
    <emphasis role="strong">时间长度</emphasis> -- 独立于时间连续统上任意点的一段时间长度。
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<emphasis role="strong">Time Interval</emphasis> -- A duration 
	of time attached to a specific point in the time continuum. 
	Also known as a time period. <sbr/>
    <emphasis role="strong">时间间隔</emphasis> -- 关联于时间连续统上某个特定点的一段时间长度。也称为时间段。
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  <para>
    Each of these temporal types has a <emphasis role="strong">Resolution</emphasis> which is defined by the smallest representable duration. A <emphasis role="strong">Time system</emphasis> provides all these categories of temporal types as well as the rules for labeling and calculating with time points. <emphasis role="strong">Calendar Systems</emphasis> are simply time systems with a maximum resolution of one day. The <emphasis role="strong">Gregorian</emphasis> system is the most widely used calendar system today (the ISO system is basically a derivative of this). However, there are many other calendar systems as well. <emphasis role="strong">UTC (Coordinated Universal Time)</emphasis> is a widely used civil time system. UTC is adjusted for earth rotation at longitude 0 by the use of leap seconds (This is not predictable, only as necessary). Most <emphasis role="strong">local time</emphasis> systems are based on UTC but are also adjusted for earth rotation so that daylight hours are similar everywhere. In addition, some local times include <emphasis role="strong">daylight savings time (DST)</emphasis> adjustments to shift the daylight hours during the summer.<sbr/>
    这些时间类型中的每一个都有一个<emphasis role="strong">分辨率</emphasis>，它由可表示的最小时间长度定义。
    一个<emphasis role="strong">时间系统</emphasis>除了提供所有这些时间类型之外，还应提供对时间点进行标注和计算的规则。
    <emphasis role="strong">日历系统</emphasis>是最简单的时间系统，它的分辨率最大，为一天。
    <emphasis role="strong">格里历</emphasis>系统是当今使用最广的日历系统(ISO系统基本上就是衍生自它)。
    不过，还有很多其它的日历系统。<emphasis role="strong">UTC (Coordinated Universal Time)</emphasis>
    是一个广泛使用的民用时间系统。因为地球的自转，UTC要通过闰秒来进行调整(这不是可预测的，只是按需要进行调整)。
    多数<emphasis role="strong">本地时间</emphasis>系统都基于UTC，但还要根据地球自转来进行调整，以使得各处白天的时间相似。
    另外，有些本地时间还包括了<emphasis role="strong">夏时制(DST)</emphasis>的调整，在夏天的时候对白天的时间进行平移。
  </para>
  <para>
    A <emphasis role="strong">Clock Device</emphasis> is software component (tied to some hardware) that provides the current date or time with respect to a time system. A clock can measure the current time to a known resolution which may be higher or lower than a particular time representation. <sbr/>
    <emphasis role="strong">时钟设备</emphasis>是一种软件组件(绑定于某个硬件)，它提供基于某个时间系统的当前日期或时间。
    时钟可以按已知的分辨率测量时间，该分辨率可能高于或低于特定的时间表示法。
  </para>
  <para>
    The library provides support for calculating with dates and times. However, time calculations are not quite the same as calculating with integers. If you are serious about the accuracy of your time calculations need to read about <link linkend="date_time.tradeoffs">Stability, Predictability, and Approximations</link>. <sbr/>
    本库提供了对日期和时间进行计算的支持。但是，时间的计算与整数的计算有点不同。如果你对于时间计算的精确性非常关注，
    那么你需要阅读 <link linkend="date_time.tradeoffs">稳定性、可预言和近似值</link> 一节。
  </para>
  <para>
    <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
      <listitem>
	<link linkend="date_time.terminology">Basic Terminology 基本术语</link>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<link linkend="date_time.calculations">Calculations 计算</link>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<link linkend="date_time.tradeoffs">Stability, Predictability, and Approximations 稳定性、可预言和近似值</link>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<link linkend="date_time.references">References 参考</link>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
</section>
