<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//Boost//DTD BoostBook XML V1.0//EN"
  "http://www.boost.org/tools/boostbook/dtd/boostbook.dtd">
<!--
Copyright Frank Mori Hess 2009

Distributed under the Boost Software License, Version 1.0. (See accompanying
file LICENSE_1_0.txt or copy at http://www.boost.org/LICENSE_1_0.txt)
-->
<section last-revision="$Date: 2007-06-12 14:01:23 -0400 (Tue, 12 Jun 2007) $" id="signals2.thread-safety">
  <title>Thread-Safety 线程安全性</title>

  <using-namespace name="boost"/>
  <using-namespace name="boost::signals2"/>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction 介绍</title>
    <para>
      The primary motivation for Boost.Signals2 is to provide a version of
      the original Boost.Signals library which can be used safely in a
      multi-threaded environment.
      This is achieved primarily through two changes from the original Boost.Signals
      API.  One is the introduction of a new automatic connection management scheme
      relying on <classname>shared_ptr</classname> and <classname>weak_ptr</classname>,
      as described in the <link linkend="signals2.tutorial.connection-management">tutorial</link>.
      The second change was the introduction of a <code>Mutex</code> template type
      parameter to the <classname>signal</classname> class.  This section details how
      the library employs these changes to provide thread-safety, and
      the limits of the provided thread-safety.<sbr/>
      Boost.Signals2 的原始动机是提供原 Boost.Signals 库的另一版本，使之可以安全地用于多线程环境。 
      做到这一点主要是通过对原 Boost.Signals API 的两个更改。一是采用了新的，依赖于 <classname>shared_ptr</classname> 
      和 <classname>weak_ptr</classname> 的自动连接管理方式，详见 
      <link linkend="signals2.tutorial.connection-management">教程</link> 的描述。
      二是 <classname>signal</classname> 类引入了模板类型参数 <code>Mutex</code>。 
      本节详述了库如何采用这些更改来提供线程安全性，以及它所提供的线程安全性的局限性。 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Signals and combiners 信号与合并器</title>
    <para>
      Each signal object default-constructs a <code>Mutex</code> object to protect
      its internal state.  Furthermore, a <code>Mutex</code> is created
      each time a new slot is connected to the signal, to protect the
      associated signal-slot connection.<sbr/>
      每个信号对象会缺省构造一个 <code>Mutex</code> 对象，以保护其内部状态。 
      此外，每当一个新的插槽连接到信号，都会创建一个 <code>Mutex</code>，以保护相关的信号插槽连接。
    </para>
    <para>
      A signal's mutex is automatically locked whenever any of the
      signal's methods are called.  The mutex is usually held until the
      method completes, however there is one major exception to this rule.  When
      a signal is invoked by calling
      <methodname alt="signalN::operator()">signal::operator()</methodname>,
      the invocation first acquires a lock on the signal's mutex.  Then
      it obtains a handle to the signal's slot list and combiner.  Next
      it releases the signal's mutex, before invoking the combiner to
      iterate through the slot list.  Thus no mutexes are held by the
      signal while a slot is executing.  This design choice
      makes it impossible for user code running in a slot
      to deadlock against any of the
      mutexes used internally by the Boost.Signals2 library.
      It also prevents slots from accidentally causing
      recursive locking attempts on any of the library's internal mutexes.
      Therefore, if you invoke a signal concurrently from multiple threads,
      it is possible for the signal's combiner to be invoked concurrently
      and thus the slots to execute concurrently.<sbr/>
      调用信号的任何方法时，信号的互斥体都会自动加锁。通常互斥体会保持锁定，直到方法结束，但是有一个重要的例外。 
      当信号通过 <methodname alt="signalN::operator()">signal::operator()</methodname> 调用时，
      该调用首先会获取信号互斥体上的锁。然后，它会获得一个句柄，指向信号的插槽链表与合并器。 
      接着，它会在调用合并器遍历插槽链表之前，释放信号的互斥体。因此，当插槽执行时，信号并没有持有互斥体。 
      选择这种设计杜绝了以下可能：插槽中运行的用户代码死锁于 Boost.Signals2 库内部使用的互斥体。 
      它还可防止插槽意外造成对库的内部互斥体递归加锁。因此，如果您从多个线程并发调用信号， 
      有可能会造成信号的合并器被并发调用，从而造成插槽并发执行。
    </para>
    <para>
      During a combiner invocation, the following steps are performed in order to
      find the next callable slot while iterating through the signal's
      slot list.<sbr/>
      在合并器的调用中，遍历信号的插槽链表时会执行以下步骤，以找到下一个可调用插槽。
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The <code>Mutex</code> associated with the connection to the
          slot is locked.<sbr/>
          插槽的连接所关联的 <code>Mutex</code> 被锁定。</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>All the tracked <classname>weak_ptr</classname> associated with the
          slot are copied into temporary <classname>shared_ptr</classname> which
          will be kept alive until the invocation is done with the slot.  If this fails due
          to any of the
          <classname>weak_ptr</classname> being expired, the connection is
          automatically disconnected.  Therefore a slot will never be run
          if any of its tracked <classname>weak_ptr</classname> have expired,
          and none of its tracked <classname>weak_ptr</classname> will
          expire while the slot is running.<sbr/>
          与插槽相关的所有被跟踪的 <classname>weak_ptr</classname> 被复制到临时的 <classname>shared_ptr</classname>， 
          并一直生存直到插槽完成调用。如果 <classname>weak_ptr</classname> 过期无法复制，连接将自动断开。 
          因此，如果插槽跟踪的任何 <classname>weak_ptr</classname> 过期，插槽就不会运行，而当插槽运行时，
          其跟踪的 <classname>weak_ptr</classname> 不会过期。
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The slot's connection is checked to see if it is blocked
          or disconnected, and then the connection's mutex is unlocked.  If the connection
          was either blocked or disconnected, we
          start again from the beginning with the next slot in the slot list.
          Otherwise, we commit to executing the slot when the combiner next
          dereferences the slot call iterator (unless the combiner should increment
          the iterator without ever dereferencing it).<sbr/>
          插槽的连接被检查，看它是否被阻塞或断开，然后，连接的互斥体被解锁。如果连接被阻塞或断开，
          则取插槽链表中的下一个插槽重新开始。否则，当合并器下一步解引用插槽调用迭代器时，
          就执行插槽，（除非合并器递增迭代器而未对其解引用）。 
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      Note that since we unlock the connection's mutex before executing
      its associated slot, it is possible a slot will still be executing
      after it has been disconnected by a
      <code><methodname>connection::disconnect</methodname>()</code>, if
      the disconnect was called concurrently with signal invocation.<sbr/>
      注意，因为我们在执行插槽前就解锁了其对应连接的互斥体，所以有可能插槽在用 
      <code><methodname>connection::disconnect</methodname>()</code> 断开后仍将继续执行，
      如在信号调用时并发调用断开。
    </para>
    <para>
      You may have noticed above that during signal invocation, the invocation only
      obtains handles to the signal's slot list and combiner while holding the
      signal's mutex.  Thus concurrent signal invocations may still wind up
      accessing the
      same slot list and combiner concurrently.  So what happens if the slot list is modified,
      for example by connecting a new slot, while a signal
      invocation is in progress concurrently?  If the slot list is already in use,
      the signal performs a deep copy of the slot list before modifying it.
      Thus the a concurrent signal invocation will continue to use the old unmodified slot list,
      undisturbed by modifications made to the newly created deep copy of the slot list.
      Future signal invocations will receive a handle to the newly created deep
      copy of the slot list, and the old slot list will be destroyed once it
      is no longer in use.  Similarly, if you change a signal's combiner with
      <methodname alt="signalN::set_combiner">signal::set_combiner</methodname>
      while a signal invocation is running concurrently, the concurrent
      signal invocation will continue to use the old combiner undisturbed,
      while future signal invocations will receive a handle to the new combiner.<sbr/>
      您可能已经注意到，在上述信号调用中，在持有信号的互斥体时，仅仅获取了信号的插槽链表与合并器的句柄。 
      因此并发调用信号仍可导致并发操作同一插槽链表与合并器。那么，如果插槽链表被更改，例如，
      当信号调用正在进行中时，并发地连接新的插槽，会发生什么事？如果插槽链表已在使用中，
      信号会在更改它之前进行深拷贝。因此，并发的信号调用将继续使用旧的未修改的插槽链表， 
      对于新建的插槽链表深拷贝的更改，将不会干扰到该信号调用。以后的信号调用收到的句柄将指向新建的插槽链表深拷贝， 
      旧的插槽链表一旦不再使用，将会被销毁。同样，如果信号调用正在运行时，
      用 <methodname alt="signalN::set_combiner">signal::set_combiner</methodname> 并发地更改信号的合并器， 
      并发的信号调用将继续使用旧的合并器而不受干扰，而以后的信号调用将会收到新的合并器的句柄。
    </para>
    <para>
      The fact that concurrent signal invocations use the same combiner object
      means you need to insure any custom combiner you write is thread-safe.
      So if your combiner maintains state which is modified when the combiner
      is invoked, you
      may need to protect that state with a mutex.  Be aware, if you hold
      a mutex in your combiner while dereferencing slot call iterators,
      you run the risk of deadlocks and recursive locking if any of
      the slots cause additional mutex locking to occur.  One way to avoid
      these perils is for your combiner to release any locks before
      dereferencing a slot call iterator.  The combiner classes provided by
      the Boost.Signals2 library are all thread-safe, since they do not maintain
      any state across invocations.<sbr/>
      并发的信号调用使用的是同一个合并器对象，这一事实意味着，你需要确保你写的任何自定义合并器是线程安全的。 
      所以，如果你的合并器需要维护状态，该状态会在合并器被调用时更改，你就可能需要用互斥体保护该状态。 
      注意，如果您在您的合并器中持有互斥体，当插槽调用迭代器解引用时，如果有个插槽导致了额外的互斥锁的发生， 
      你就会有死锁和递归锁的危险。避免这些危险的一个方法是，让你的合并器在信号调用迭代器解引用之前释放锁。 
      Boost.Signals2 库提供的合并器类都是线程安全的，因为它们在调用之间并没有维护任何状态。
    </para>
    <para>
      Suppose a user writes a slot which connects another slot to the invoking signal.
      Will the newly connected slot be run during the same signal invocation in
      which the new connection was made?  The answer is no.  Connecting a new slot
      modifies the signal's slot list, and as explained above, a signal invocation
      already in progress will not see any modifications made to the slot list.<sbr/>
      假设用户写了个插槽，该插槽把另一个插槽连接到调用的信号。在同一信号调用中，这个新连接的插槽会不会运行？ 
      答案是否定的。连接新的插槽更改了信号的插槽链表，正如上文所述，正在进行的信号调用将不会看到对插槽链表的任何更改。
    </para>
    <para>
      Suppose a user writes a slot which disconnects another slot from the invoking signal.
      Will the disconnected slot be prevented from running during the same signal invocation,
      if it appears later in the slot list than the slot which disconnected it?
      This time the answer is yes.  Even if the disconnected slot is still
      present in the signal's slot list, each slot is checked to see if it is
      disconnected or blocked immediately before it is executed (or not executed as
      the case may be), as was described in more detail above.<sbr/>
      假设用户写了个插槽，该插槽把另一个插槽从调用的信号断开。在同一信号调用中，这个被断开的插槽是否无法运行？ 
      如果它在插槽链表中出现的位置在那个断开它的插槽之后呢？这一次，答案是肯定的。 
      即使被断开的插槽仍然存在于信号的插槽链表中，每个插槽在执行（或视情况并不执行）前， 
      会检查它是否已被断开或阻塞，这在上文中已有详述。
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Connections and other classes 连接与其他类</title>
    <para>
      The methods of the <classname>signals2::connection</classname> class are thread-safe,
      with the exception of assignment and swap.  This is achived via locking the mutex
      associated with the object's underlying signal-slot connection.  Assignment and
      swap are not thread-safe because the mutex protects the underlying connection
      which a <classname>signals2::connection</classname> object references, not
      the <classname>signals2::connection</classname> object itself.  That is,
      there may be many copies of a <classname>signals2::connection</classname> object,
      all of which reference the same underlying connection.  There is not a mutex
      for each <classname>signals2::connection</classname> object, there is only
      a single mutex protecting the underlying connection they reference.<sbr/>
      <classname>signals2::connection</classname> 类的方法是线程安全的，除了赋值和交换swap。 
      这是通过对象底层的信号-插槽连接所对应的互斥体加锁实现的。赋值和交换不是线程安全的，
      因为互斥体保护的是底层的连接，它是由 <classname>signals2::connection</classname> 对象所引用的， 
      而不是 <classname>signals2::connection</classname> 对象本身。也就是说，可能有许多份 
      <classname>signals2::connection</classname> 对象的拷贝，所有拷贝都引用了同一个底层连接。 
      没有针对每个 <classname>signals2::connection</classname> 对象的互斥体，只有一个互斥体保护它们所引用的底层连接。
    </para>
    <para>The <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> class obtains some thread-safety
      from the <code>Mutex</code> protecting the underlying connection which is blocked
      and unblocked.  The internal reference counting which is used to keep track of
      how many <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> objects are asserting
      blocks on their underlying connection is also thread-safe (the implementation
      relies on <classname>shared_ptr</classname> for the reference counting).
      However, individual <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> objects
      should not be accessed concurrently by multiple threads.  As long as two
      threads each have their own <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> object,
      then they may use them in safety, even if both <classname>shared_connection_block</classname>
      objects are copies and refer to the same underlying connection.<sbr/>
      <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> 类因为有保护其底层连接的 <code>Mutex</code>， 
      从而获得了一些线程安全性，该底层连接即被阻塞和解除阻塞的连接。其内部引用计数也是线程安全的
      （实现依赖于 <classname>shared_ptr</classname> 的引用计数），该引用计数用来跟踪有多少 
      <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> 对象宣称阻塞它们的底层连接。然而，单个的 
      <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> 对象不应该从多个线程并发访问。
      只要两个线程都有自己的 <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> 对象，那么它们可以安全地使用它们， 
      即使这两个 <classname>shared_connection_block</classname> 对象是复制关系，并指向同一个底层连接。
    </para>
    <para>
      The <classname alt="slotN">slot</classname> class has no internal mutex locking
      built into it.  It is expected that slot objects will be created then
      connected to a signal in a single thread.  Once they have been copied into
      a signal's slot list, they are protected by the mutex associated with
      each signal-slot connection.<sbr/>
      <classname alt="slotN">slot</classname> 类没有内置的内部互斥锁。插槽对象应该在一个线程内创建，
      然后连接到信号。它们一旦被复制到信号的插槽链表，它们就会被每个信号-插槽连接所关联的互斥体所保护。
    </para>
    <para>The <classname>signals2::trackable</classname> class does NOT provide
      thread-safe automatic connection management.  In particular, it leaves open the
      possibility of a signal invocation calling into a partially destructed object
      if the trackable-derived object is destroyed in a different thread from the
      one invoking the signal.
      <classname>signals2::trackable</classname> is only provided as a convenience
      for porting single-threaded code from Boost.Signals to Boost.Signals2.<sbr/>
      <classname>signals2::trackable</classname> 类不提供线程安全的自动连接管理。 
      特别是，它留下了一种可能性，如果可跟踪子类对象在不同于引发信号的线程中被销毁， 
      信号调用可能会进入部分析构对象。提供 <classname>signals2::trackable</classname> 
      仅仅是为了方便单线程代码从 Boost.Signals 移植到 Boost.Signals2。
    </para>
  </section>
</section>
